疑犯追踪 第1季 第11集
Person of Interest S01E11 720p HDTV x264
你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know, because I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
But it sees everything...
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
不管你是被害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
If your number's up, we'll find you.
发现里瑟了  关闭摄像机
Got eyes on Reese. Kill the cameras.
该回家了  约翰  以前的事就让它过去吧
Time to come home, John. Slate's been wiped clean.
你知道这是不可能的
You know that'll never happen.
今晚第三个了  看来是满月啊
Third one tonight. Must be a full moon.
你叫法鲁克・马达你
Your name is Farouk Madani.
你是纳贾夫[伊拉克城市]最好的大夫
You were the best surgeon in Najaf,
但你却没钱申请美国的医师资格证
But you can't afford a license in the States
因为你的钱都寄回家了
because you send all your money home to family.
帮他缝合  别问问题
Stitch him up-- no questions asked--
你就能重新做医生了
and you can be a doctor again.
警察  所有人都下来
Police. Everybody out.
纽约警局  都下车
NYPD! Come out of there!
有什么问题吗  警探
Yhere a problem, detective?
你们盯梢基地组织时也这么毛糙吗
Are you guys this sloppy when you tail al-qaeda?
这地方不错  出来散步吗
Cute place. You gonna be out for a while?
对了  你们不毛糙
Right, this isn't you being sloppy at all.
你这是在示威
This is you making a point.
据我们所知  你是唯一一个和他
You're the only person we know of who's had any contact
-有联系的人  -如果我有他的消息
- with our boy. - If I hear from him,
一定立刻告诉你们  但这一套
you'll be the first to know, but all this?
-没必要  -是吗
- Unnecessary. - Is it?
我真惊讶他居然能逃脱
You know, I was really surprised he was able to slip away.
真搞不明白他怎么做到
Just can't figure out how he did it.
这已经不是我的案子了  你慢慢玩吧
It's not my case anymore, so you have fun with that.
我和你一样不喜欢这样  卡特
I don't like this any more than you do, Carter.
昼夜不停地盯梢
Watching someone night and day,
你不知道会有什么发现
you never know what you'll dig up.
我见过有人就这么失去了工作和家人
I've seen it ruin careers, families.
威胁警察是犯法的  斯诺先生
Threatening a police officer is against the law, Mr. Snow.
对联邦探员撒谎也是
So is lying to a federal agent.
我会盯着你
I'll be seeing you.
好吧  你会把密码放在...
Okay, where would you keep...
这人是他的同伙
This guy's his partner, and it turns out
现在发现其实我有他的手机号码
I've had his cell phone number for weeks now.
你所拨打的号码不在服务区
The number you have reached is not in service.
你要是用我的电脑  干脆帮我把报告写了
You're gonna use my computer, you gotta do my reports too.
你好  我是纽约警局的卡特警探
Hi, detective Carter, NYPD.
我要你给我所有这个
I need all the locations data you've got
接不通的手机的定位信息
on a disconnected cell phone.
是在诺曼・伯戴特名下
Yeah, name's "Burdett, norman."
917-555-0131
这人是谁
So who's this guy?
我就是在查
That's what I'm trying to find out.
我还以为只有你们老板才会这种排场
I thought these folks were just for your boss.
抱歉要用这种地下党的方式接头
Sorry about all the cloak-and-dagger.
什么风把你从首都吹来了
So what brings you up from D.C.?
你
You.
-我真是受宠若惊  艾丽夏  -别
- I'm flattered, Alicia. - Don't be.
我的人要你给个说法
My people want answers.
国安局为你们公司提供监视录像三年了
Your company has had the N.S.A. feeds for three years.
不是我们公司  只是我而已
Not my company, just me.
要是国会知道了你在造的这台机器
If congress knew about this machine you're building,
还有我们给你的无限制权限
about the unfettered access we've given you
让你接触到我们美国公民的资料
to all the data we're compiling on U.S. Citizens,
不会只是关门而已  你会去坐牢
You wouldn't just be shut down. You would go to jail.
估计不会让我俩同监室吧
I don't suppose they'd let us be cell mates.
你得汇报进展  奈森  否则我们就撤出
We need progress, Nathan, or we're pulling the plug.
-这是什么  -这就是进展
- What's this? - It's progress.
-只有九位数字吗  -你是做情报工作的
- Nine digits? - You work in intelligence.
自己破解吧
Figure it out.
我真想有那么一次让你来处理这种事
For once, I'd like you to handle one of these meetings
而我躲在暗处
while I lurk in the shadows.
你试试看就知道不可能了
You couldn't lurk if you tried.
我们给她的那个号码  最好能成功
That number we gave her... it better pan out.
会的
It will.
你怎么知道
How?
我不知道  但是机器知道
I don't know. But the machine does.
-有点信心啊  奈森  -对你还是机器
- Have a little faith, Nathan. - In you or in the machine?
好  海耶斯先生  就是这里了
Okay, Mr. Hayes, this is the place.
当心脚下
Watch your step--uh...
不是说你的脚  这只是
Not your step, I mean-- it's just one of those things
一个惯用说法  无意冒犯
people say, you know? No--no offense.
我们这里有轮椅通道  如果有什么需要
But we got ramps all over the place, so if you need anything--
我几天后就能站起来了
I'll be on my feet in a few days.
好  有什么问题就给我电话
Yeah, but if anything goes wrong, you call me.
我是管理员  我叫柴斯克
I'm the super. Name is Trask.
-我跟你说过了吗  -两次了
- I tell you that already? - Twice.
看来我是老了
I guess I'm getting old.
想当年我通宵在迈阿密派对狂欢
It seems like yesterday I was partying till dawn
仿佛就在昨天啊
down in miami.
我以前在那里有六家夜店
Used to own six nightclubs down there.
以前我在科勒尔盖布尔斯有栋豪宅
You know, I had a mansion in Coral Gables,
一只白色孟加拉虎  不得不放弃这一切
a white bengal tiger... had to give all that up.
对我健康不好  你呢
Bad for my health. What about you?
你是哪儿人  干什么的
Where you from? What do you do?
怎么坐上轮椅了
How'd you wind up in that chair?
我晚上不太顺
I had a rough night.
好吧
Okay.
给你钥匙  有什么需要
Here are the keys. You need anything,
就拨租约上我的号码
my number's on that lease.
我的名字是  你知道了
The name is-- well, you know.
一切满意吗  里瑟先生
Everything satisfactory, Mr. Reese?
好地方
Nice place.
不过真是劳您费神了
You really shouldn't have gone to this much trouble, though.
不麻烦  我想你已经受够了宾馆了
No trouble--I thought you'd get tired of hotels,
另外照你的情况看  我感觉
and, in your condition, I felt that something a bit more
你还是低调些好
low-profile was in order.
我们的好伙伴斯诺呢
Where's our pal snow?
眼下正忙着盯着卡特警探
Preoccupied with detective Carter at the moment.
她还好么
She all right?
不是我不关心这个女人
Not that I don't share your concern for the woman
但她想把你交给中情局
who tried to hand you over to the CIA--
她放我们走了  只是
She did let us go. Just...
在我休养的这段时间里
Keep an eye on her for me for a while,
帮我留意她一下
while I'm resting up.
这个嘛
About that...
我不是来这休息的是吧
I'm not here to rest, am I?
机器不等人啊
I'm afraid the machine waits for no man.
下一个号码是谁
So who's the next number on your list?
-你刚见过他  -那个管理员吗
- You just met him. - The super?
詹姆斯先生  给你换过淋浴喷头了
Mr. James, got that shower head for you.
-多谢  -你好吗  帕克夫人
- Thanks. - How you doing, mrs. Park?
我很好  多谢
Oh, fine, thanks.
少打些电话  艾伦  会辐射大脑
Ease up on the phone, Aaron. It'll nuke your brain.
好吧  谢谢  欧尼
Yeah, thanks, Ernie.
大厨莉莉  真是美女
Lily the cook, I love how you look.
谢谢  欧尼  你自己写的诗吗
Thanks, ernie. You write that one yourself?
欧尼斯特・P・柴斯克  51岁
Ernest p. Trask, 51 years old.
生于佛罗里达的古德兰  人口394
Born in Goodland, Florida, population 394.
小镇子在数码资料存储方面
Small towns aren't exactly paragons
可不是什么先进模范
Of digital record-keeping, but I did verify
不过我查到他有高中毕业证书
he got a high school diploma.
我猜猜 没有什么夜店  豪宅
Let me guess. No nightclubs, no mansions,
还有什么宠物老虎
No pet tigers?
看来柴斯克先生想象力丰富
Mr. Trask seems to have a vivid imagination.
你就没什么东西要收拾么
Don't you have anything to unpack?
轻装简行
I travel light.
-知道谁是威胁吗  -暂时不知道
- Any idea what the threat is? - Not yet.
他当了14年管理员了
He's been super for 14 years.
工作生活在同一个地方
Lives and works in the same place.
所以不管柴斯克身上要发生什么事
So whatever's gonna happen with Trask,
多半会发生在这里
it will probably happen here.
这栋楼里有多少人
How many people in the building?
-241个  -那就是241个嫌犯咯
- 241. - so 241 suspects?
也许只有一个
Or maybe just one.
我擅自黑入了柴斯克的在线电话账单
I took the liberty of hacking into Trask's online phone bill
他上周给三家典当行打了电话
He called three pawn shops last week,
那种店铺专门贩卖不经登记
The kind that specialize in off-the-books sales
难以追查的手枪
of untraceable handguns.
柴斯克可能计划要杀死某个人
Trask might be planning to kill somebody.
-你没给我带一杯吗  -无功不能受禄
- You didn't get me anything? - Coffee's for closers.
我给你射杀里瑟的大好机会  你失手了
I got you a clear shot at Reese and you whiffed.
我的目的不是杀死他  是你说
I wasn't aiming to kill. You said you wanted
你想问他在鄂尔多斯发生了什么
to question him about what happened in Ordos.
我是说"有可能的话"
If possible.
那是次要目的
Secondary objective.
她在干什么
What's she up to?
据我们所见  在赶一些文件工作
Near as we can tell? Catching up on paperwork.
她没有用她的电脑或手机
She's not using her computer or phones.
里瑟呢
Reese?
我们安排人查了300英里半径内
We got people checking every hospital, clinic,
所有医院  诊所  停尸房
and morgue in a 300-mile radius.
只要有人救他  我们就能查到
If anybody stitched him up, we'll pick up the scent.
希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind
我除了必要的硬件之外
but in addition to the necessary hardware
还买了些书给你读
I brought a few books for you to read...
还有一点乔迁贺礼
and a little housewarming gift.
-多谢了  -想试试吗
- Thanks. - You want to try it out?
不用了  我现在挺好
No. I'm--I'm good for now.
你以后会感谢我
You'll thank me later.
柴斯克似乎是个无伤大雅的牛皮大王
You know, Trask may seem like a harmless bag of wind,
不过我之前也上过当
but I've been fooled before.
既然他买了枪  我想知道为什么
If he bought a gun, I'd just like to know why.
只有一个办法能查出来
Only one way to find out.
黑入他的无线网络吗
We're going to hack his wi-fi?
黑入所有的无线网络
We're gonna hack all of them.
如果威胁来自这栋楼
If the threat's in the building,
我们就得认识一下邻居们
we should get to know our neighbors.
你已经进入16个网络了吗
You're into 16 networks already?
电讯公司提供无线网络服务时
When the phone company puts in your wi-fi,
初始密码就是手机号码
the password is your phone number.
大部分人根本不会改
Most people never even change it.
就算是改了的也不难搞定
The other ones might actually take a minute.
我们一黑入  就打开所有的网络摄像头
Once we're in, we can turn every webcam,
保姆监视器  安全系统  手提电脑网络
nanny cam, security system, and laptop on the network
变成了我们的耳目
into our eyes and ears.
就像那台机器一样
Just like the machine.
把一栋公寓楼想象成整个世界  算是吧
I suppose...if one apartment building were the entire world.
厨师莉莉似乎在和公寓顶层的瑞克约会
Lily the Cook seems to be dating Rick from the penthouse
而714房间的安珀
And Amber in 714 is...
真健康
Healthy.
我有些怀疑到底是什么触动了机器
Somehow I doubt that's what alerted the machine.
有发现了  芬奇
Got one, Finch.
道格・斯坦利  保安人员
Doug Stanley, security guard.
他正在追捕一名从女子公寓
He's been hunting a thief who's been stealing jewelry
偷走珠宝的小偷
out of women's apartments.
也许柴斯克就是那个小偷  想要杀死道格
Maybe Trask is the thief planning to kill Doug,
以掩盖其罪行
to cover his crimes.
又或者柴斯克知道谁是小偷
Or Trask knows who the thief is
所以小偷计划杀了他
and now they're planning to kill him.
那是房东  阿兰・霍特
That's the landlord, Alan Holt.
柴斯克看起来可不像明星雇员
Doesn't look like Trask is the employee of the month.
也许他打算扭断老板的脖子
Maybe he's about to snap and kill his boss?
为什么机器要给出他的社保号码
Why did the machine give us his number?
柴斯克有麻烦了
Is Trask in trouble...
还是他就是麻烦
Or is he the problem?
傻盯着墙是得不出答案的
Well, you're not gonna get it staring at the wall.
得出去搜集点情报
We need to do some legwork.
好吧
Right.
我就位了  麻烦快点
I'm in position. Make it quick, please.
柴斯克先生  我是521的约翰・海耶斯
Mr. Trask, it's John Hayes in 521.
-我这边出了点问题  -我马上到
- I'm having a bit of a problem. - I'll be right there.
该死  该死  该死
Damn it, damn it, damn it.
我安装好摄像头了  里瑟先生
I've planted the cameras, Mr. Reese.
现在开始搜查
I'm starting to search.
自从奥珀尔飓风袭击了我的游艇后
I haven't seen damage like this since hurricane Opal
我就再没见过这么严重的情况了
trashed my yacht.
1995年发生在阿拉巴马州的超级飓风
简直就像有人用锤子敲了似的
Looks like somebody went at this with a hammer.
没发现枪
No sign of a gun.
但我可不信他只是在收集子弹
But I doubt if he's just a collector of bullets.
那么他到底想杀谁
So who does he want to shoot?
果然  带的工具又错了
Of course, I didn't bring the right one.
我去去就来
I'll be right back.
柴斯克需要管扳钳  芬奇
Trask needs a pipe wrench, Finch.
-他下去了  -好了  马上
- He's coming back down. - Okay, just a minute.
芬奇  他在院子里  朝你过来了
Finch, he's in the courtyard headed your way.
走路要带眼睛  柴斯克
Watch where you're going, Trask.
芬奇
Finch.
他为她痴狂了
He's obsessed with her.
看来我们不是唯一在
I'm afraid we're not the only ones
监视邻居的人  里瑟先生
spying on our neighbors, Mr. Reese.
哈罗德  快出去
Harold, get out of there now.
芬奇  你出去了吗
Finch, did you get out of there?
芬奇
Finch?
你是什么...
Who the hell--
回来
Hey! Come here!
你在我家干什么
What were you doing in my place?
帮我一把
I could use a hand here.
好  坚持住  坚持住
Okay, hang on, hang on, hang on.
他要关闭电梯
Okay, he's gonna kill the elevator.
保安  我是柴斯克
Security, this is Trask.
芬奇  他在西边的楼梯井
Finch, he's in the west stairwell.
右拐  从西边上去
Turn right, take the east stairs up
过三层  你就到家了
Three flights and you're home.
不过要快  他40秒后就到你这层了
But move quick, he'll be on your floor in about 40 seconds.
我感觉就像迷宫里的老鼠
I feel like a rat in a maze.
你是怎么应付这些的
How do you put up with this?
道格  我刚刚撞到一个入侵者
Doug, I just caught a guy breaking in.
他就在我公寓里
He was just in my apartment.
继续走  芬奇  你不会有事的
Keep walking, Finch. You'll be fine.
身高175  带眼镜  有点瘸
5'9", glasses. He walks with a limp.
我猜他可能就是你在找的小偷
I think he might be that thief you've been looking for.
这保安在那间公寓干什么呢
What was that security guard doing in that apartment?
芬奇
Finch...
我肯定道格知道你不是小偷
I'm pretty sure Doug knows you're not the thief.
他才是
He is.
我把证据发给你
And I'm sending you the proof.
-手机不错  -给你看样东西
- Nice phone. - Can I show you something?
道格  他在不在  你看到他了吗
Doug, is he up there? Have you found him yet?
我们可以报警
So we can call the police...
或者你忘了见过我  我也忘了见过你
Or you can forget you saw me, and I'll forget I saw you.
我要去查下一层
I'm gonna check the next floor.
他不在第二层
He's not on two.
柴斯克有武器  对莉莉怀有危险的狂热
So Trask is armed, has a dangerous fixation on Lily,
刚刚还追了我三层楼
and he just chased me up three floors.
可以蛮有把握地说  他就是凶手了
Safe to say he's our perpetrator.
我不确定  芬奇  你真的不想去
I don't know, Finch. Sure you don't want to
复核一下你的机器吗
double-check with your machine?
你要不要每次都说这个笑话啊
Yes, that joke never gets old.
哈罗德  没事吧
Harold, is everything okay?
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
有人来了
We have company.
抱歉我们不请自来了  奈特
Sorry to pop up unannounced, Nate.
我们总该不是喝多了要闲扯吧
I guess we're not doing this over drinks.
他在这儿工作
He works here.
就算是我  偶尔也需要技术支持
Even I need technical support sometimes.
奈森  你还记得威克斯副局长吧
Nathan, you remember deputy director Weeks.
大权在握的人  希望我没惹上什么麻烦
The man in charge. I hope I'm not in trouble.
你给我们的那9个数字是个社保号码
The nine digits you gave us are the social security number
是戈登・科兹威尔的  他是我们的人
of a man named Gordon Kurzweil. He's one of ours.
他是国防情报局官员  身份绝密
He's a D.I.A. case officer. Top secret clearance.
藏身联调局二十年了
Been acing F.B.I. background checks for 20 years.
我们监视了科兹威尔两个星期  一无所获
We surveilled Kurzweil for two weeks, got nothing.
就在我们以为是你耍花招
And just when we were thinking that you'd sold us
糊弄我们的时候  他行动了
a bill of goods, he breaks pattern.
动作还不小
goes for a drive.
一位叙利亚商人在贝塞斯达一个公园落了部手机
At a park in Bethesda, a Syrian businessman drops his phone.
美国马里兰州中部城市
库兹韦尔捡到它  通过加密的短信
Kurzweil picks it up, and via coded S.M.S.，
他安排了一比交易
he arranges to sell 26 pounds of
向伊朗政府出售26吨的武器级铀
weapons-grade uranium to the Iranian government.
超过最低标准的武器级的核武器器材用料
看来号码确实起作用了
So I guess the number panned out?
我要你解释给我听
What I need you to explain to me is...
为什么联邦特工都不能发现的叛徒
How did some damn computer program spot a traitor
某台天煞的电脑却能发现
when federal agents couldn't?
其实  我也不知道
Honestly? Not a clue.
机器能及时提供行动情报
The machine will deliver actionable intelligence
以阻止任何危及国家安全的威胁
in time to thwart any threat to national security.
但它的操作系统是个黑匣子
But its operating system is a black box.
如果我们想用这台机器锁定特定目标呢
And if we want to direct this machine at a specific target?
没这个必要
No need.
它监视着每个目标
It already watches every target.
你这对我们的要求可有点高啊  奈森
You're asking us to take a lot on faith here, Nathan.
一个我们不能检查
A piece of software we can't inspect,
不能控制  也不能更改的软件
can't control or modify
只有靠它的感觉为我们提供情报吗
that only feeds us Intel when it feels like it?
它能觉察到威胁
When it perceives a threat.
我很抱歉  伙计们  但这是我们保护
Look, I'm sorry, folks, but it's the only way
它和我们自己的唯一方法
that we can keep it and us protected.
如果没人看见机器监测到的东西
If no human sees what the machine sees,
那理论上来讲
then technically,
没人的第四修正案权利[指隐私权]被侵犯
no one's fourth amendment rights have been violated.
英格拉姆先生  你何不就关心自己的公司
Why don't you just focus on your computer, Mr. Ingram,
而把违反宪法权利的问题留给我们
and leave the constitutional concerns to us?
因为我也是名美国公民
Because I'm a citizen too, and I'm a lot more comfortable
而且让机器监视我的一举一动这种事
having this machine watch my every move
我亲自来做比让你们做更舒坦
than someone like you.
所以它一直是个封闭系统
So it will remain a closed system,
完全独立
fully autonomous?
而我们知道的只是一个号码
All we get is a number?
一个号码不是足够让你抓到科兹威尔了吗
Did you need more than a number to pick up Kurzweil?
这台机器提醒你留意某个人  而你照做了
The software told you to take a closer look, so you did.
它是个黑匣子
It's a black box.
就是这样  接不接受随你便
That's the deal. Take it or leave it.
我不习惯被个合同承包人指手画脚
I'm not accustomed to having contractors dictate terms.
如果你提供的是有缺陷的软件
If you're going to be supplying crippled software,
那我们可能需要重新商议价钱
maybe we need to revisit the question of price.
不如你来告诉他商议好的价钱吧  艾丽夏
Why don't you tell him the price negotiated, Alicia?
英格拉姆先生认为这个项目
Mr. Ingram felt that this project was his duty
是他作为公民而非商人的责任
as a citizen, not a businessman.
他造了机器  却只要一美金的回报
He's building the machine for one U.S. Dollar.
我猜我别无选择了
I suppose I don't have a choice.
我就知道
I know, I know.
我不知道自己还能做些什么
I don't know what to do anymore.
除了拒绝我还能说些什么  他一直都在
How else to say no. He's always right there.
即使我看不见他  我感觉得到他在监视我
Even when I can't see him, I can feel his eyes on me.
是把撞匙
It's a bump key.
就像硬件黑客
A hardware hack.
插进去  转一下  再震一下
Just stick it in, twist, give it a little jolt...
它就能打开这栋楼的所有锁
And it'll open any lock in the building.
你不会再被人逮到了  放心
You won't be caught with nowhere to run again.
那个柴斯克你迷恋的女人
And this is everything you've found on the woman
这是你查到的所有资料吗
that Trask is obsessed with?
莉莉・桑顿  在佐治亚州长大
Lily Thornton. Grew up in Georgia,
在她爸爸的餐馆里做厨师
cooking in her dad's diner.
一流厨师  05年毕业
Cordon bleu, class of 05.
09年前一直住在她阿姨家
Staying in her great aunt's apartment since 09.
现在是曼哈顿一家顶级餐厅燃起的新星
And currently a rising star at a top Manhattan bistro.
在同瑞克・莫里斯交往
Romantically linked to Rick Morris,
一名有势力的餐厅老板
A powerful restaurateur.
干得不错  里瑟先生
This is very nice work, Mr. Reese.
我以前也用过电脑
Well, I have used a computer before.
但我们看不到她房间的录像
But we can't get video from her place.
她每天都会改无线上网密码
She changes her wi-fi password every day.
随机字母和数字
Random alphanumerics.
你会喜欢有安全意识的女孩
You gotta love a girl with good security habits.
所以柴斯克一直在偷拍她
So Trask has been snapping pictures of her.
我们能肯定这说明他要杀她吗
Are we sure that means he wants to kill her?
76%的女性被害人在被杀前
76% of all female homicide victims are stalked
都被跟踪过
before they're murdered.
我会盯着她
Well, I better keep an eye on her then.
你不是要跟着她去上班吧
You're not tailing her to work?
这玩意我已经用上手了
I'm getting pretty good at this thing.
是啊  而我肯定中情局打死你的时候
Yes, I'm sure the C.I.A. will be deeply impressed
可会相当佩服你呢
when they shoot you.
我坐不住了  芬奇
Just feeling a little restless here, Finch.
用那个坐垫啊
Use the cushion.
号码是不等人的  芬奇
The numbers never stop coming in, Finch.
要是在我行动不便的时候
What are we gonna do if another one comes in
出现另一个号码怎么办
while I'm sidelined?
我肯定我会有办法
I'm sure I'd think of something.
我知道你不带枪
And I know you won't carry a gun,
但如果我要你外出行动
but if I'm sending you back in the field,
你一定要带点能自卫的东西
you're getting some basic self-defense.
-我真觉得没有...  -不  听着
- Oh, I really don't think-- - No, listen up.
如果柴斯克攻击你  你就用手指
If Trask comes at you, put your fingers straight out
这么往他的眼睛里插
like this and strike at his eyes.
戳他眼睛  这就是你所谓的技巧吗
Poke him in the eyes? That's your technique?
不  那是你要学的技巧  如果那没用
No, that's your technique, and if that doesn't work,
你就用大拇指  挤他眼窝
you can always take your thumb, jam it in his eye socket,
不停地转  直到你打中他的头
and twist till you hit his brain.
别说了
Please, stop.
柴斯克还在院子里
Trask is still in the courtyard,
但莉莉工作的时候得有人看着
But I want eyes on Lily at work.
我马上就去
I'll be with her shortly.
如果柴斯克想要杀她
If she is Trask's intended victim,
那我最好能看到她房间里面
I'd like a better view of the inside of her apartment
而不是只透过窗户偷窥
instead of simply peering at her through a window.
里瑟先生  她家里已经个摄像头了
Mr. Reese, there's already a camera here.
无线的基本款
Basic consumer model. Wireless.
连至一个隐藏的网络
Streaming to a hidden network.
配对的接收器
The receiver it's paired with
可能在这栋房子的任何地方
could be anywhere in the building.
看来柴斯克监视着她的一举一动
I think Trask has been watching her every move.
我想莉莉已经被监视得够多了
And I think Lily's been spied on enough.
手机定位数据
Cell phone location data.
你这是去哪
Hey, where you going?
把自己搞晕了
To get lost.
擦干净了要提取指纹
Need to dust this for prints.
-给你  -你把它弄坏了
- There you go. - I think you broke it!
不会看说明书吗
So? Read a book.
先生  我是纽约警察  现在要借你的外套
Sir? NYPD police. I need your jacket now.
你要征用我的外套吗
You're requisitioning my jacket?
出租车
Taxi!
去皇后区  45街和21街的交叉口
Queens, corner of 45th and 21st.
你们有麻烦了
Hey, you guys got a real problem.
卡特查到了你们的一个手机
Carter's got info from one of your cell phones.
她在追查你
She's tracking you.
我知道她在找我
I'm aware that she's looking for me.
我想你也不知道为什么
I don't suppose you know why.
还不明白  我们那位朋友还好吗
No, not yet. How's our guy?
还活着  躲起来了
Alive. Hidden.
你收到我寄去的包裹吗
Did you receive the package I sent?
在我手上呢
Yeah, I got it right here.
怎么  安非他明吃完了吗
What, did you run out of adderall?
上面有我们那位朋友的指纹
Our friend's prints are on it.
我要你帮个忙  让他摆脱中情局的追踪
I need you to throw the C.I.A. off his trail.
来次公路旅行吧  警探
Take a road trip, detective.
康涅狄格这时最美了
Connecticut's nice this time of year.
-菜还合胃口吗  -好吃极了  谢谢
- Is everything good? - It's great. Thank you.
-你们确定...  -下午好  芬奇先生
- You make sure you try... - Good afternoon, Mr. Finch.
莉莉那边怎么样了
How's it going with Lily?
这也许是有史以来最有口福的监视行动
This may be the best-catered stakeout in history.
芬奇  别在那吃东西
Don't eat in the field, Finch.
你不知道何时要行动
Never know when you'll have to move fast.
房东的邮件查出什么了吗
Any progress on the landlord's email?
还在查
Still working on that one.
我在莉莉家找到的摄像头呢
What about the camera I found at Lily's?
如果我们能证明那是柴斯克的
If we can trace it to Trask,
他就会被解雇
we can get him fired,
甚至可能被捕
maybe even arrested.
我还在尝试破解隐藏的无线网络
Still trying to break into the hidden wireless network.
密码还没破解出来
No luck cracking the password yet.
但我找到了些其他信息
But I did find out some information
关于我们那位朋友柴斯克
About our friend Trask.
原来他曾经有过一个老婆
Turns out there used to be a Mrs. Trask.
-曾经  -她十三年前人间蒸发了
- Used to? - she disappeared 13 years ago.
柴斯克从没报过警
Trask never called the cops.
跟别人说她去波卡拉顿和家人住了
Told everyone she went to be with family in Boca Raton.
那我猜她肯定没去
And I'm guessing she's not in boca.
在我看来
Far as I can tell...
她哪都没去
She's not anywhere.
或许莉莉不是他的第一个被害人
Maybe Lily's not his first.
我的天
Oh, my god.
我可以肯定她知道自己有个跟踪狂
And I think it's safe to say she knows she has a stalker.
艾伦
Hey, Aaron?
你能帮我把这些都扔掉么
Can you just throw these away for me?
当然可以
Yeah, sure.
可怜的女娃子真遭罪
Poor girl seems miserable.
她刚把一件礼物扔进垃圾堆
She just threw a gift in the trash.
一捧玫瑰
Bouquet of roses.
出租车
Taxi!
伯戴特  你的最后落脚点是在这里
So, this is where your trail ends, Burdett.
接下来你会去哪
Where'd you go from here?
你这是在浪费时间  警探
You're wasting your time, Detective.
我今早刚刚伪造了地点信息
I falsified the location data this morning.
我敢打赌你的真名肯定不叫伯戴特
I'm gonna go out on a limb and guess your name isn't Burdett.
你觉得找到我就能找到我的搭档么
Do you think finding me will lead you to my partner?
你还想继续你的逮捕归案
Are you still trying to make that arrest?
不了  他那些中情局哥们不让我管了
Oh, no. His C.I.A. Pals got that out of my system.
我要的是抓住他  不是杀掉他
I wanted to catch him, not kill him.
那你现在想要什么
What do you want now?
还在想
Still working that out.
但如果我要继续对着政府特工撒谎
But if I'm going to keep lying to government agents
好保护你们俩  我就得有个极好的理由
To protect you two, I'm gonna need a damn good reason.
我要答案
I want answers.
我要知道你们都做的什么
I need to know what you do.
转身  警探
Turn around, Detective.
你朋友怎么样了
How's your friend?
你总得跟我讲清楚
You're gonna have to tell me something.
比如你们都是什么人
Like who the hell are you,
还有现在这算怎么个情况
And what exactly is going on here?
我九岁的时候  我的兄弟们认为
When I was nine years old, my brothers decided
我该去学游泳  于是他们就把我扔进了
I needed to learn swim, so they tossed me
泳池里最深的区域
Into the deep end of the pool.
花了我点时间  但是我总算会游了
Took a few minutes, but I figured it out.
你看见那人了吗  警探
Do you see that man, Detective?
他的名字叫德雷克・华生  39岁
His name is Derek Watson, 39 years old.
18个月之前  他没了工作
18 months ago, he lost his job.
他曾想方设法地供他的按揭
He tried to keep up with the mortgage as best he could,
但最终还是断了炊
But the money ran out eventually.
没了房子  很快又没了老婆
Lost his house, and his wife left soon after.
德雷克・华生将要卷入一起暴力犯罪
Derek Watson is about to be involved in a violent crime.
我不知道具体会是什么  但相信我
I don't know what exactly, but believe me,
很快就会有事发生
Something is gonna happen.
那种事你不可能知道
You can't know that.
你带了你的勤务枪了吗  警探
Did you bring your service weapon, Detective?
很抱歉就这么把你扔进深水区了
Sorry to toss you into the deep end,
但是  你也知道  我的朋友身体不适
But, as you know, my friend is indisposed.
纽约警局凶杀组
NYPD homicide.
我是卡特
It's Carter.
我要对下述人员做背景调查  德雷克・华生  39岁
I need a background on a Derek Watson, 39 years old.
我查到一个弗农山的德雷克・H・华生
I show a Derek H. Watson in Mount Vernon.
两个月前房屋被提前收回
House was foreclosed two months ago.
没有现住址
No current address.
就是他了  你有什么信息
That's him. What do you got?
没啥  没前科  没逮捕记录
Not much. No priors, no arrests.
有几张违章停车罚单没交
A couple of unpaid parking tickets,
但是就这些
But that's about it.
对了  强制收回他房子的是哪家银行
Hey, what's the name of the bank that took his house?
金鼎信贷
Truprime Mortgage.
银行那边是谁签的文件
Who filed the paperwork for the bank?
约翰・达尔顿  这是一起调查中的谋杀案么
John Dalton. Is this for an open homicide?
我一会儿再跟你说这个
I'll have to get back to you on that.
地球上最强的监侦训练
Finest surveillance training on the planet,
却搞不定一个纽约警察
And a New York cop gave you the slip.
还愣着作甚  难不成她人在这车里
Well, I know she's not in here, guys.
里瑟还没有死  那么就是说
Reese hasn't turned up dead, so odds are
他找到了个安全屋  扩大搜索范围
He's found a safe house. Expand the search.
过去两天里出租的公寓或是酒店房间都要查
All apartments and hotels rented in the last two days.
-但是如果他  -少说话  多办事
- But if he's anywhere-- - just...make it happen.
你看得到柴斯克么  里瑟先生
You have eyes on Trask, Mr. Reese?
你他喵的上哪去了
Where the hell have you been?
现在你知道我的感受了
Now you know how I feel.
莉莉要回家了  她这样安不安全
Lily's headed home. Is it safe for her there?
我现在正看着柴斯克
I'm watching Trask right now.
而且我也不确定她是不是目标
And I'm not sure she's his target.
我认为柴斯克或许是瞄准了瑞克
I think Trask might be after Rick.
-怎讲  -他花了整个下午
- Why? - Well, he spent the afternoon
在瑞克的房间周围游荡
Sniffing around Rick's apartment.
根据目前掌握的情况  我敢说他在给瑞克挖坟
If I didn't know better, I'd say now he's digging a grave.
柴斯克弄掉那男友
Trask gets rid of the boyfriend
这样就能把莉莉据为己有了
And has Lily all to himself.
一切可好吗
Everything all right?
还行  就是闷得慌
Yeah, I'm just sick of being cooped up
还有屏幕看得眼睛都花了
And, uh, staring at screens all day.
我宁可做这些活  也好过
I'd rather be doing that than trudging around
跑遍半个曼哈顿
Half of Manhattan.
我还分神去查了莉莉的计程车票
I have half a mind to spot Lily cab fare.
芬奇  你最快多久能到
Finch, how fast can you get here?
大概15分钟  怎么了
About 15 minutes. Why?
因为我们没时间了
Because we just ran out of time.
我认为柴斯克今晚就会有行动
I think Trask is making his move tonight.
看邮箱那  莫里斯先生
Checking your mail, huh, Mr. Morris?
-可不是嘛  -我说那啥
- Looks like it. - Yeah, I think I, uh,
我想我知道你家为啥漏水了
I think I figured out why your place is flooding.
就是要一个特制的水龙头
It just, uh, it just needs a special faucet.
我们一起下去看看如何
Why don't we, uh, why don't we go downstairs and check it out?
如果你觉得没问题  我明天就能给你装上
If, uh, if you like it, I can install it tomorrow.
保证再也不漏水  所以我们
No more floods. So why don't we go
-一起去地下室看看呗  -我很忙  好不好
- Down to the basement? - I-I'm busy, all right?
我没时间看这看那  快点给我弄好就行
I don't need to see anything, just have it fixed.
你得离莉莉远点
You need to stay away from Lily.
说啥
What?
你疯了吗
Have you lost your mind?
我叫了辆车  五分钟就能到
I've called the car. I can be there in five.
那就太迟了
That'll be four minutes too late.
她不爱你  明白吗
She doesn't love you, man. All right?
你必须得离开她
You need to leave her alone.
你丫想老牛吃嫩草想疯了吧  柴斯克
You got some kind of pathetic old-man crush here, Trask?
是不是要干翻我  然后带她出去跳舞啊
Gonna punch me out, take Lily to the dance?
你又不是他男朋友  你更不是她的英雄
You're not her boyfriend, and you're not her hero.
你丫就是个清洁工
You're just the damn janitor.
所以要是我马桶塞了  我会找你的
So if my toilet clogs, I'll let you know.
否则的话  靠边站
Otherwise, step aside.
房子哪里着火了
Is the building on fire?
我保证一切都好  F夫人
I'm sure everything's fine, Mrs. F,
但我马上就去例行检查  好吗
But I'm gonna go check it out just the same, all right?
我回到家发现东西被动了
I come home and things have moved,
就好象他进过我公寓一样
Like he's been inside my apartment.
我很害怕他还会做什么
I'm scared of what he's going to do.
芬奇  这还没完  柴斯克还会再犯
Finch, this isn't over. Trask will try again.
而且他还是很痴迷莉莉
And he's still obsessed with Lily.
也许我们该采取些更激进的手段了
Perhaps we should consider more aggressive tactics.
收到我送你的花了吗
你为什么不给我电话
我们得谈谈
我能看到你
他在恐吓她
He's terrorizing her.
我今晚就要柴斯克滚出这栋公寓
I want Trask out of the building tonight.
-海耶斯先生  -我不叫海耶斯
- Mr. Hayes. - My name isn't Hayes.
那  我就得请你离开了
Well, then I'm gonna ask you to leave.
事实上
Actually...
你才是那个要走的人
You're the one who'll be leaving.
我不知道你以为你...
Hey, I don't know what you think--
我知道所有事情  那些玫瑰  短信
I know about the roses, and the texts,
- 还有藏起来的摄像头  -不  我绝没有
- And the hidden camera. - No, I would never--
我知道你有枪  柴斯克  我也知道你想
I know about the gun, Trask, and I know you were ready
今晚就杀掉那个男友
To kill her boyfriend tonight.
他不是她男朋友
He's not her boyfriend.
你不明白
You don't understand.
现在  你必须卷铺盖离开这个地方
Now, you're gonna pack your bag and leave this place.
并且不管你觉得你又多么的爱她
And no matter how much you think you love her,
你永远都不能回这里来
You're never coming back.
拜托
Please...
我热爱这份工作
I love this job.
我也确实在乎莉莉  但不是你想的那样
And I do care for Lily, but not like that.
真的不是
Not like that.
芬奇  柴斯克没有拍那些莉莉的照片
Finch, Trask didn't take those photos of Lily.
他是从顶层公寓偷的
He stole them from the penthouse.
我知道
I know.
他也没有安摄像头
He didn't plant the cameras either.
柴斯克不是尾行的人
Trask isn't the stalker.
你不喜欢那些花吗  宝贝
Didn't you like the flowers, babe?
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
我以为今晚就我们二人世界了
I thought it could just be you and me tonight.
求你走吧  请你离开
Please, go. I want you to go.
来吧  宝贝
Come on, baby.
你知道你其实并不想我走
You know you don't want me to leave.
里瑟先生  我们得靠你帮一把了
Mr. Reese, we're gonna need a little help.
滚出我的公寓
Get out of my apartment now.
你其实并不这样想
You don't mean that.
瑞克  求你  住手吧
Rick, please. This has to stop.
别再来什么电话  什么花了
The phone calls, the flowers--
拜托  那些只是对你我
Come on. Those were just a little
昨晚约会的小小谢意
"Thank you" for our date last night.
那不是约会  我们只是去了同一个派对
That wasn't a date. We were going to the same party.
你这勾人的小妖精
You're such a tease.
你要我跟你乘一辆出租
You made me share a cab with you
然后就跟踪了我一个晚上
and then you followed me all night.
我只是想帮你罢了  心肝儿
I'm just trying to help you, Sweetie.
得了  我能为你做很多事
Come on, I could do so much for you in this town.
我能让你当上总厨
Make you executive chef.
我不想为你工作  我只要你离开
I don't want to work for you, I just want you to leave.
那个管理员让我离你远点
The super told me to stay away from you.
你  是不是跟他说了什么
Did you---- tell him about us?
你是不是撒谎说你不爱我
Did you lie and say you don't love me?
没有
No.
你为什么要这么伤害我  宝贝
Now, why would you want to hurt me like that, baby?
我也喜欢我伤害你吗
Would you like it if I hurt you?
不
No--
我所做的一切都是为了你  莉莉
All I've ever done is look out for you, Lily.
你也该表示点谢意了
It's time you showed a little gratitude.
放开她  莫里斯先生
Let her go, Mr. Morris!
我告诉过你  离她远点
I believe I told you to leave her alone.
有发现了
We got something.
北康涅狄格有家兽医诊所被人硬闯了
Break-in at a veterinary clinic in Northern Connecticut.
现场发现了印有
Reese's prints were on a prescription bottle
里瑟指纹的药瓶
found at the scene.
你不会一边开车一边告诉我吗
Couldn't be telling me this while we drive?
"匿名线索"个屁
"Anonymous tip" my ass.
这肯定是谁在恶作剧
This has gotta be some kind of joke.
行了  走吧  手放到背后
All right, let's go. Hands behind your back.
血压90到50
B.P. 90 over 50.
脉搏微弱  肋骨骨折  内出血
Thready pulse, multiple fractures, bleeding internally.
我对他说了我没兴趣  然后
I told him that I wasn't interested, and...
他好像受了什么刺激一样
and it was like something in him snapped.
变得更加固执  更加狂躁
He became obsessive and, um, very unstable.
他跟踪了我几个月了  但我一直吓得
He's been stalking me for months, but I was too afraid
不敢告诉别人
to tell anyone.
要不是欧尼及时赶到...
And if Ernie hadn't shown up when he did--
这没什么
That wasn't nothing.
你该看看他们迈阿密
Should've seen some of the guys
派来追杀我的人
they sent after me back in Miami.
你可不会想惹上古巴黑手党的人
You do not want to mess around with the Cuban mafia.
-轻点儿  -抱歉  先生
- Ow--easy. - sorry, sir.
给你
Here.
-这是什么  -柴斯克的枪
- What's this? - Trask's gun.
好吧
Good.
他的真名不是欧内斯特・柴斯克
You know, his name isn't Ernest Trask,
而是欧内斯特・马沙杜
It's Ernesto Machado.
他之前在迈阿密有六间夜总会
He used to own six nightclubs in Miami,
一艘游艇  科勒尔盖布尔斯的豪宅  还有
a yacht, house in Coral Gables, and...
一只宠物老虎
a pet tiger.
全是真的
It was all true.
就连那些有害他健康这点也是真的
Even the part about it being bad for his health.
他在1996年出庭指证了古巴黑手党
He testified against the Cuban mafia in 1996.
至今还在被人追杀呢
Still a price on his head.
他是受保护的证人
He's in witness protection.
所以我们找不到柴斯克太太
That's why you couldn't find Mrs. Trask.
她跟着他从迈阿密来到纽约
She came with him from Miami,
但失去了豪宅和夜店  她撑不下去
But without the houses and the clubs she didn't last long.
她离开了他  去了亲戚那里  在波卡拉顿
She left him, moved in with relatives-- in Boca Raton.
你是怎么查出来的
How'd you find all that out?
我擅长电脑
I'm good with computers.
坦白说吧  芬奇
Be honest, Finch.
根本就没有机器  是不是
There is no machine, is there?
只有你
It's just you.
有下个号码时我会准备好
I'll be ready when the next number comes.
真有意思  这还用你说
Funny you should mention that.
有枪
Gun!
放下  放下
Drop it! Drop it!
没事  纽约警局  已经安全了
It's all right. NYPD. Everything's under control.
趴着
Get down.
卡特警探  这个  就是我们的工作
That, detective Carter, is what we do.
干得好  我的朋友
Well done, my friend.
现在  告诉我
Now, tell me...
那台机器到底是
What on earth was it that made the machine
怎么挑出科兹威尔的号码
pick out Kurzweil's number?
你要我揭密吗
You want me to pop the hood?
当然
Yeah.
2002年11月
November 2002.
这也不是最早的时间
This isn't the first item chronologically,
但是最先引起了机器的注意
but it's the one that triggered a harder look.
-就一张加油站收据吗  -有18张
- A gas station receipt? - 18 of them...
都来自马里兰州陶森市外的加油站
from a shell station just outside Towson, Maryland.
每个月的第三个星期四  科兹威尔
Kurzweil stopped there every third Thursday
都会在那停留  即使前一天已经加满了油
of every even month, even if he'd filled up the day before.
而这18次中有3次
On 3 of his 18 visits,
这辆SUV会在两小时前出现
This SUV was present two hours before.
情报秘密传递点
A dead drop.
那辆SUV登记在
The SUV was registered to the wife
一位土耳其石油大亨妻子的名下
of a Turkish oil executive that paid for plane tickets
而此人曾为一个伊朗人购买过两张机票
used by an Iranian suspect in the bombing
而该伊朗人曾涉嫌1994年在
of a Jewish community center
布宜诺斯艾利斯的犹太社区爆炸案
in Buenos Aires in 1994.
这点微弱的线索把科兹威尔联系了起来
The thinnest thread connects Kurzweil and his contact
而机器看了出来
and the machine could see it.
它发现了  而且它是对的
It knew, and it was right.
机器对我们每一个人都时刻记录吗
It does this all the time...to all of us?
这太可怕了
That's...terrifying.
你是除我之外
It's probably a good thing that
唯一一个看到这机器如何运作的人
you're the only other person that will ever see
这大概是件好事吧
how this machine works.
完成后  我要加密到极致
When it's complete, I'll encrypt the O.S. so completely
确保这世界上没有一台电脑能入侵它
that no computer on earth will ever crack it.
你不为此烦恼吗  我是说
Does it bother you? I mean...
你的成就具有历史意义
What you've achieved is historic.
却无人得知
But no one will ever know.
只有这样才能保证
It's the way it has to be to be sure.
保证什么
Sure of what?
保证它会按我的意愿被使用
Sure that they'll use it the way I intended.
你认为政府会滥用这台机器
So you think the government would abuse this machine?
丹顿・威克斯花了六个月
Denton Weeks has spent the last six months trying
设法把这台机器弄到国安局
to tunnel into the machine by way of the N.S.A. feeds.
他失败了  但他不会放弃
He's failed, but he'll keep trying.
而且这么想的人不只他一个
And he won't be alone.
我简直不敢想象  如果威克斯这种人
I don't even want to think about what a man like Weeks
拥有了这种力量  后果会何等可怕
would do with that kind of power.
所以我们一定要保证他和其他任何人
That's why we have to keep him or anyone else
永远不能染指这台机器
from ever getting their hands on it.
你确定是威克斯吗
You sure it was Weeks?
机器告诉我的
The machine told me.
它有自我防卫的本能
It has an instinct for self-preservation.
你说得好像它是活的一样
You talk about that thing like it's alive.
他能听到你的话
It can hear you.
侦测到潜在威胁
奈森・英格拉姆
疑犯追踪 第1季 第11集
Person of Interest S01E11 720p HDTV x264
YYeTs人人影视